Yuanyuan (Lilian) Sun

		<i>J</i> · · · · (,			
ெ Chicago, IL, USA	© 312 825 9892	🖄 lilian.swen@out	look.com	in LinkedIn	GitHub	Portfolio
Summary						
Highly motivated grad experience. Extensive b maintenance. Exception Processing, Data Storag	background in full s nal problem solver v	oftware development vith an aptitude for tr	lifecycle in	ncluding design ng. Proficiency	, coding, testing in OOP, Data Pr	, debugging, reparation &
Education						
Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL, USA Suzhou University of Science and Technology, Suzhou, China			M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.67/4.0) Dec. 2023 B.S. in Computer Science and Technology Jun. 2016			
Tech Skills						
Java, Spring Frameworkski SQL, NoSQL Git, SVN, CI/CD Ton	JavaScript, HTMI	L, CSS, React AWS	Cloud Serv	ices, Docker Co	ontainers, Kuber	netes, Linux

Senior Software Engineer Mar. 2019 - Dec. 2021 Shanghai Highly Electric Co., Ltd

Experience------

- Provided estimates for web app development & test. Selected libraries and open-source technologies for project integration. Oversaw full lifecycle of software development with on-time delivery while staying 5% under budget.
- Designed scalable service architecture. Re-architected old and complex applications by applying a unifying framework. Improved operational efficiency, reliability, adaptability. Decreased user complaints by 65% and reduced the cost of operation & maintenance by 15% from 2020 to 2021.
- Developed reusable, scalable APIs. Supported building & deployment of new products and features & tests. Implemented and executed Stress Testing on high-concurrency interfaces.
- Mentored junior developers & summer interns.

Mar. 2017 - Mar. 2019 **Junior Software Engineer** Shanghai Mathartsys Co., Ltd Shanghai, China

- Analyzed user requirements, designed functional and flexible web services by UML, collaborated with BA, QA to create detailed design documentation, unit test plans, well-documented code.
- Created RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on J2EE, Spring Framework, Spring Boot. Researched and evaluated methods & techniques to resolve problems, reduced friction in development lifecycle.
- Managed & maintained 11 enterprise web applications, patched & improved features. Embraced automation, streamlined the build and deployment process. Documented and presented reports to leadership twice a month.
- Revamped web applications, improved security applications, minimized hacker attacks from 33.3% to 3.2%.
- Fixed bugs and streamlined documented procedures to increase DevOps efficiency by 20% from 2018 to 2019.

Android System Dev Intern Feb. 2016 - Jun. 2016 Pactera Technology International Ltd. Shanghai, China Burned the Android OS source code in devices, developed and improved features on the native applications via SDK. Cooperated with QA team to improve user interfaces. Top 10% intern on bug fix release in the Android framework R&D team.

Major Projects-----





